<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software-Team on Dvir Segal&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/software-team/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software-Team on Dvir Segal&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/software-team/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Leading with no authority</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/leading-with-no-authority-khl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/leading-with-no-authority-khl/</guid>
      <description>As individual contributors, occasionally we encounter various situations where we need to lead without formal authority (sometimes we’ve been asked to). Formal training on leading others without the power to do so is rare. The fact, finding the right candidates for this critical task is challenging for any management, doesn’t assist much in the circumstances. The root cause relies on the required skill set for being one since a potential candidate doesn’t follow typical hiring procedures and job description.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Social Glue of the Team’s Lunch</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-social-glue-of-the-team-s-lunch-32ed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-social-glue-of-the-team-s-lunch-32ed/</guid>
      <description>Everybody has to eat, right? Families like to eat together, and friends frequently meet for dinner, and colleague regularly socialize over lunch.&#xA;Recent research by Cornell University found that employees who ate meals together had significantly better team performance at work than those who didn’t.&#xA;“During the study, we noticed that not sharing mealtimes was a signal that something deeper was wrong with the way the group worked , something that was then reflected in the team’s performance.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
