<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on dvirsegal</title>
    <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on dvirsegal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Developer story: Getting used to macOS as a long-time Windows user</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/developer-story-getting-used-to-macos-as-long-time-windows-s-user-30o0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/developer-story-getting-used-to-macos-as-long-time-windows-s-user-30o0/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s like learning to ride bicycles whole over again&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;As long as I recall my relationship with computers, I’ve been using Windows. I customized everything to the perfection that fits my needs. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s keyboard shortcuts, specific applications (like this one) that helped do my work, scripts, and more. If it can be modded or automated — I’ve done it.&#xA;Recently it all changed. 😱😱😱&#xA;I decided to take a new position.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A brief introduction to YAML</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/are-we-all-yaml-engineers-now-538j/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/are-we-all-yaml-engineers-now-538j/</guid>
      <description>What is YAML? And how it works?&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;Recently I switched jobs, and as part of this change, I’ve been introduced to a whole new tech stack. RabbitMQ 🐰, Java Spring, Docker, etc. (meaning more subjects to write about 😂). Most of the technologies I use on a daily basis consume YAML as their configuration. In this post, I’ll try to illustrate what I’ve learned (and from where) while trying to understand this new world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations and welcome aboard!</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/congratulations-and-welcome-aboard-3iba/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/congratulations-and-welcome-aboard-3iba/</guid>
      <description>The importance of a well crafted, humane onboarding process&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;You’ve prepared a new resume, searched for challenging positions, submitted your CV to various companies, participated in many interviews, asked your interviewers about the working environment, considered your culture fit. Eventually, you’ve received several job offers, prioritized and weigh them down …. and finally, you’ve agreed to take one. 🤗&#xA;Found a new job, yay&#xA;The exciting day has arrived — your first day on the job.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A letter to the lonely developer</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/a-letter-to-the-lonely-developer-458f/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/a-letter-to-the-lonely-developer-458f/</guid>
      <description>Me against a bug, reminding myself how to solve any defect&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;Dear developer,&#xA;Don’t give up, keep up with your efforts to find other ways to understand the bug’s root cause. I know it can be frustrating. The agonies with the process can be ruff. But, you’ve got it, you solved many in the past, and you will solve this one too. It is part of your job.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everybody was cargo culting</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/everybody-was-cargo-culting-46n5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/everybody-was-cargo-culting-46n5/</guid>
      <description>My personal experience to jump off the bandwagon (effect)&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;Imagine the following situation. One of your experienced colleagues talks about doing some work, which she’s passionate about and sure it will provide better results for the team. She has fire in her eyes when she talks about replacing technology X with Y.&#xA;You feel it right into your heart. Your colleagues seem to agree with her. She’s so right.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diving into the deep code waters</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/diving-into-the-deep-code-waters-57p9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/diving-into-the-deep-code-waters-57p9/</guid>
      <description>Tools and techniques for exploring an unknown (large) codebase&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;You’ve received a new responsibility or walked into a new job where there is existing code to work with. The source control has been introduced to you, realizing you have a lot to learn. Now what? Asking yourself, how should I become acquainted with the new codebase? Which for some, may be intimidating. Below I’ll attempt to illustrate my techniques for getting familiarity with the code, leading to structured knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effort estimation — it’s complicated</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/effort-estimation-it-s-complicated-4bdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/effort-estimation-it-s-complicated-4bdb/</guid>
      <description>Effort estimation — it’s complicated&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;On the dilemma of evaluating software development effort&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;For the past few months, estimating effort, a long-standing dilemma of the software industry, bothers me. How should we, as SW engineers, deal with the accuracy of effort estimations? The answer is complicated and has implications over developers’ career growth, having an impact on personal development. There is much at stake.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code review guidelines light the way</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/code-review-guidelines-light-the-way-1e4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/code-review-guidelines-light-the-way-1e4/</guid>
      <description>My humble opinion on the necessity of a check-in process&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;Are you familiar with the situation of getting a code review that is being delayed by your peer reviewer’s nitpicking for filling his code perfection aspirations? Unable to commit due to build server failure? Personal preferences overruled over technical facts?&#xA;Let me see your unit tests&#xA;All the above are examples of the necessity of a well-defined procedure, guiding us in various situations we encounter daily.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building trust through effective communication</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/building-trust-through-effective-communication-208c/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/building-trust-through-effective-communication-208c/</guid>
      <description>You can achieve almost anything by teamwork. Listening is a vital characteristic of a leader. Effectively communicating your thoughts is essential, as well. How you interact can positively and negatively affect the relationships you have in your work (and personal life too).&#xA;Effective communication is defined by various articles (#1, #2, #3, and more), and I challenge myself not to repeat them. I would like to give a different perspective on the matter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Notes are your life dashboard</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/digital-notes-are-your-life-dashboard-2ep9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/digital-notes-are-your-life-dashboard-2ep9/</guid>
      <description>As time goes by, I’ve started to find myself overwhelmed with things I would like to achieve. I looked for a solution to track my progress and goals. I tried various tools and found that writing each item and organize them in lists works for me. I felt immediate relief and “in-control” of my things. Curios of the reason why — it has drawn me to read about it and realizing that when writing things down, it frees your mind, clear space for more important topics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arrange your time and your mind will follow</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/arrange-your-time-and-your-mind-will-follow-4ljh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/arrange-your-time-and-your-mind-will-follow-4ljh/</guid>
      <description>Being productive by taking control of your time&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;A gym workout, a reminder to walk the dog, meeting with your colleagues on that project presentation, a dentist appointment — are all on the same page. You can’t separate artificially between your work and personal calendars. Why? Because that’s how your life works. The goal is to see what your actual day looks like, to blend between work and personal life for finding the right balance that fits you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code comments are your code autobiography</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/code-comments-are-your-code-autobiography-3c7n/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/code-comments-are-your-code-autobiography-3c7n/</guid>
      <description>Writing about your code is redundant; the code is all you need. I can invest my time on unit tests or develop other features, and other excuses of why writing code comments is a waste of time. It’s a common belief among developers.&#xA;Well, you’ve invested all your efforts in cultivating the design of your code, why should you comment it, right? As a result, code documentation is either absent or useless.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Estimating partial human poses</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/estimating-partial-human-poses-178n/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/estimating-partial-human-poses-178n/</guid>
      <description>A lot has been said on OpenPose. This real-time multi-person groundbreaking keypoints detection method has many features, along with:&#xA;2D real-time multi-person keypoint detection 3D real-time single-person keypoint detection Calibration toolbox Single-person tracking Supporting Python API, Unity Plugin, Cuda, OpenCL, and CPU only Moreover, more features are in the works by the team (Gines Hidalgo, Zhe Cao, Tomas Simon, Shih-En Wei, Hanbyul Joo, Yaser Sheikh, and Yaadhav Raaj) at Carnegie Mellon University.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ditto, the clipboard manager that saved me</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/ditto-the-clipboard-manager-that-saved-me-1j8h/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/ditto-the-clipboard-manager-that-saved-me-1j8h/</guid>
      <description>Copy-pasting is one of those things that you do every day while working on a computer. By doing so, each time you invest a small portion of your daily routine.&#xA;Say you want to share a photo\text\whatever with a friend from a website, you copy it, either by right-clicking on it and copying it to the clipboard or using Ctrl+C and then paste it to your favorite sharing application and after doing so, you’ve realized you want to share it again with another person.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
