<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>softwaredevelopment on dvirsegal</title>
    <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/tags/softwaredevelopment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in softwaredevelopment on dvirsegal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://dvirsegal.github.io/tags/softwaredevelopment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A brief introduction to YAML</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/are-we-all-yaml-engineers-now-538j/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/are-we-all-yaml-engineers-now-538j/</guid>
      <description>What is YAML? And how it works?&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;Recently I switched jobs, and as part of this change, I’ve been introduced to a whole new tech stack. RabbitMQ 🐰, Java Spring, Docker, etc. (meaning more subjects to write about 😂). Most of the technologies I use on a daily basis consume YAML as their configuration. In this post, I’ll try to illustrate what I’ve learned (and from where) while trying to understand this new world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations and welcome aboard!</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/congratulations-and-welcome-aboard-3iba/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/congratulations-and-welcome-aboard-3iba/</guid>
      <description>The importance of a well crafted, humane onboarding process&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;You’ve prepared a new resume, searched for challenging positions, submitted your CV to various companies, participated in many interviews, asked your interviewers about the working environment, considered your culture fit. Eventually, you’ve received several job offers, prioritized and weigh them down …. and finally, you’ve agreed to take one. 🤗&#xA;Found a new job, yay&#xA;The exciting day has arrived — your first day on the job.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everybody was cargo culting</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/everybody-was-cargo-culting-46n5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/everybody-was-cargo-culting-46n5/</guid>
      <description>My personal experience to jump off the bandwagon (effect)&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;Imagine the following situation. One of your experienced colleagues talks about doing some work, which she’s passionate about and sure it will provide better results for the team. She has fire in her eyes when she talks about replacing technology X with Y.&#xA;You feel it right into your heart. Your colleagues seem to agree with her. She’s so right.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diving into the deep code waters</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/diving-into-the-deep-code-waters-57p9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/diving-into-the-deep-code-waters-57p9/</guid>
      <description>Tools and techniques for exploring an unknown (large) codebase&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;You’ve received a new responsibility or walked into a new job where there is existing code to work with. The source control has been introduced to you, realizing you have a lot to learn. Now what? Asking yourself, how should I become acquainted with the new codebase? Which for some, may be intimidating. Below I’ll attempt to illustrate my techniques for getting familiarity with the code, leading to structured knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code comments are your code autobiography</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/code-comments-are-your-code-autobiography-3c7n/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/code-comments-are-your-code-autobiography-3c7n/</guid>
      <description>Writing about your code is redundant; the code is all you need. I can invest my time on unit tests or develop other features, and other excuses of why writing code comments is a waste of time. It’s a common belief among developers.&#xA;Well, you’ve invested all your efforts in cultivating the design of your code, why should you comment it, right? As a result, code documentation is either absent or useless.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
