<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>softwaredevelopment on dvirsegal</title>
    <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/tags/softwaredevelopment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in softwaredevelopment on dvirsegal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://dvirsegal.github.io/tags/softwaredevelopment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to use docker-compose, volumes, networks, and more</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/how-to-use-docker-compose-volumes-networks-and-more-4a24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/how-to-use-docker-compose-volumes-networks-and-more-4a24/</guid>
      <description>This is the last post in the simplify docker series ( if you haven&amp;rsquo;t read the previous ones, go ahead and read them, it will make more sense afterward — part I &amp;amp; part II). This time I’ll cover networks, docker-compose, docker volumes, and more.&#xA;What is it all about with docker-compose?&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;Docker-compose allows you to define and run multi-container Docker applications. With Compose, you configure your app’s services using YAML files (more on YAML here).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to run, delete a Docker image</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/how-to-run-delete-a-docker-image-52dm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/how-to-run-delete-a-docker-image-52dm/</guid>
      <description>I covered the basics of creating and building Docker images in part I (if you haven’t read that yet, I would recommend it since this part is based on it). In this part, I’ll explain how to run and delete an image of the container you’ve built.&#xA;let’s continue&#xA;Running an image is as simple as docker run -it image_name:tag . Let’s break it down; tag is the one you set when building it; note that if you remove it, then docker assumes you point to the latest.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to create &amp; build a Docker image</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/how-to-create-build-a-docker-image-56o3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/how-to-create-build-a-docker-image-56o3/</guid>
      <description>I’ve heard a lot about dockers, even had some experience with it as part of my graduate degree. Still, as the old saying goes, learning is by doing. By doing, I mean using the stuff you want to learn as part of your daily work (instead of using it as part of a course in a semester since it will be forgotten). Actually, this is a technology that, in my perspective, should be in some familiarity level in each software engineer’s tech stack.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A brief introduction to YAML</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/are-we-all-yaml-engineers-now-538j/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/are-we-all-yaml-engineers-now-538j/</guid>
      <description>What is YAML? And how it works?&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;Recently I switched jobs, and as part of this change, I’ve been introduced to a whole new tech stack. RabbitMQ 🐰, Java Spring, Docker, etc. (meaning more subjects to write about 😂). Most of the technologies I use on a daily basis consume YAML as their configuration. In this post, I’ll try to illustrate what I’ve learned (and from where) while trying to understand this new world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How demo-oriented programming makes you better</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/how-demo-oriented-programming-makes-you-better-44mo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/how-demo-oriented-programming-makes-you-better-44mo/</guid>
      <description>On the focused effort of making a working prototype&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;There are many ways you can determine whether a new feature will add value to the product or turn out to be a complete waste of time. For instance, you can undertake user research, analyze the demands of the market, and study existing solutions. However, we (developers) have a fantastic tool in our sleeves: Developing a running project that demonstrates the proposed solution’s key ideas is your optimal option — in my opinion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations and welcome aboard!</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/congratulations-and-welcome-aboard-3iba/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/congratulations-and-welcome-aboard-3iba/</guid>
      <description>The importance of a well crafted, humane onboarding process&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;You’ve prepared a new resume, searched for challenging positions, submitted your CV to various companies, participated in many interviews, asked your interviewers about the working environment, considered your culture fit. Eventually, you’ve received several job offers, prioritized and weigh them down …. and finally, you’ve agreed to take one. 🤗&#xA;Found a new job, yay&#xA;The exciting day has arrived — your first day on the job.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everybody was cargo culting</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/everybody-was-cargo-culting-46n5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/everybody-was-cargo-culting-46n5/</guid>
      <description>My personal experience to jump off the bandwagon (effect)&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;Imagine the following situation. One of your experienced colleagues talks about doing some work, which she’s passionate about and sure it will provide better results for the team. She has fire in her eyes when she talks about replacing technology X with Y.&#xA;You feel it right into your heart. Your colleagues seem to agree with her. She’s so right.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diving into the deep code waters</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/diving-into-the-deep-code-waters-57p9/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/diving-into-the-deep-code-waters-57p9/</guid>
      <description>Tools and techniques for exploring an unknown (large) codebase&#xD;Link to heading&#xD;You’ve received a new responsibility or walked into a new job where there is existing code to work with. The source control has been introduced to you, realizing you have a lot to learn. Now what? Asking yourself, how should I become acquainted with the new codebase? Which for some, may be intimidating. Below I’ll attempt to illustrate my techniques for getting familiarity with the code, leading to structured knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code comments are your code autobiography</title>
      <link>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/code-comments-are-your-code-autobiography-3c7n/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://dvirsegal.github.io/posts/code-comments-are-your-code-autobiography-3c7n/</guid>
      <description>Writing about your code is redundant; the code is all you need. I can invest my time on unit tests or develop other features, and other excuses of why writing code comments is a waste of time. It’s a common belief among developers.&#xA;Well, you’ve invested all your efforts in cultivating the design of your code, why should you comment it, right? As a result, code documentation is either absent or useless.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
